A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 1958-1989, 1996-2013.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Dept. of Conservation and Recreation,
1958-1989, 1996-2013.
The Library of Virginia
31845, 32266, 32548, 32762, 33166, 33518, 33858, 34313, 51260
Virginia. Dept. of Conservation and Recreation.
174.5 cu. ft.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Dept. of Conservation and Recreation is an outgrowth of the Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development which became known as the Dept. of Conservation and Historic Resources on 1 January 1985. It was later renamed the Dept. of Conservation and Recreation on 1 July 1989 when the Division of Historic Landmarks split off and became its own agency.
Scope and Content
Includes correspondence and subject files documenting actions, planning, functions, implementation of agency programs, and the establishment of policies and procedures, as well as achievements of the Dept. of Conservation and Recreation and its predecessors. Contains correspondence, news clippings, programs, financial records, memoranda, news releases, newsletters, agendas, minutes, legislative files, state parks and historic sites information, reports, and environmental impact statements.
Includes information on coal mining, forestry, litter control, and mined land reclamation.
Alphabetical.
Acquisition Information
Accession 31845 was transferred by the Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development, July 14, 1983.
Accession 33166 was transferred by Department of Conservation & Historic Resources, June 3, 1988
Virginia. -- Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development.
Virginia. -- Dept. of Conservation and Historic Resources.
Virginia. -- Dept. of Conservation and Recreation
Virginia Conservation Commission.
Conservation of natural resources -- Virginia.
Environmental impact statements -- Virginia.
Historic sites -- Virginia.
Parks -- Virginia.
Recreation -- Virginia.
Agendas. -- aat.
Correspondence. -- aat.
Financial records. -- aat.
Minutes. -- aat.
Press releases. -- aat.
State government records. -- aat.
Virginia. -- Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development.
Virginia. -- Dept. of Conservation and Historic Resources.
Contents List
- Correspondence and subject files, 1958-1980 (Accession 31845)., Extent: 67 cubic feet (67 boxes)
  - Administration, Division of
    - Office Space - New Supreme Court Building, 1968-1969. (Box 1)
    - Publications (All Divisions), 1967-1972. (Box 1)
    - Publications - Departmental Handbook draft, 1972-1973. (Box 1)
    - Accidents, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Capital Outlay - Quarterly Reports, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Change of Address letters, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Contributions - UGF, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Credit Cards, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - General correspondence, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Invitations - JSG, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Invitations - JFM, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Invitations - ASR, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Invitations - MMS, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence - JFM, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence - ASR, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence - MMS, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Requests for conservation information, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Vouchers, 1974-1975. (Box 1)
    - Capital Outlay - Quarterly Reports, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Change of Address letters, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Credit Cards, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Expenses, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - General correspondence, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Invitations, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Office Space - General, 1961-1976. (Box 1)
    - Office Space - Leases, 1964-1976. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Publications - Printing of Departmental Booklet, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Requests for conservation information, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
    - Speech material (Sutherland), 1961-1976. (Box 1)
    - Travel authorizations, 1971-1976. (Box 2)
    - Contributions - UGF, 1975-1976. (Box 2)
    - Capital Outlay - Quarterly reports, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Change of Address letters, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Employee Handbook, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - General correspondence, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Invitations, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Requests for conservation inforamtion, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Travel authorizations, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Contributions - UGF, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
    - Audio-Visual supplies, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Capital Outlay - Quarterly reports, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Central Garage Pool, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Requests for conservation information, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Change of address letters, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - General correspondence, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Correspondence - Fred W. Walker, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
    - Retirement - M. M. Sutherland (12/31/77), 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - General correspondence - Fred W. Walker, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence - Fred W. Walker, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Travel authorizations, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Contributions - UGF, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Capital Outlay - Quarterly Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Change of address letters, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - General correspondence, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Invitations, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Metric System Converstion, 1974-1979. (Box 3)
    - Natural Heritage Day, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence - Fred W. Walker, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Public Information Policy - News releases, etc. from all divisions, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Requests for conservation material, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing Tournament, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing quarterly reports, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
    - Travel authorizations, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
    - United Givers Fund Campaign, 1978. (Box 4)
    - Virginia Outdoor Writers, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
    - Captital Outlay - Quarterly reports, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Change of address letters, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - General correspondence, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Invitations, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Correspondence - Fred W. Walker, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Public Information Policy - News releases, etc. from all divisions, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - General, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Salt Water Sport Fishing - Lamination of citations, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - Travel authorizations, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
    - United Givers Fund Campaign, 1979. (Box 4)
    - Virginia Outdoor Writers, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
  - Forestry, Division of
    - Railroads - Rights of Way, 1965-1966. (Box 5)
    - Mountain Tree Nursery (Augusta County), 1966-1967. (Box 5)
    - Cumberland State Forest - Land, 1966-1971. (Box 5)
    - George W. Dean - Retirement and Award, 1973-1974. (Box 5)
    - Financial Statements, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
    - General correspondence and information, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1971-1973. (Box 5)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
    - Financial Statements, 1975-1976. (Box 6)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1975-1976. (Box 6)
    - General correspondence and information, 1975-1976. (Box 6)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee (3 folders), 1975-1976. (Box 6)
    - Financial Statements, 1976-1977. (Box 6)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1976-1977. (Box 6)
    - General correspondence and information, 1976-1977. (Box 6)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1976-1977. (Box 6)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1976-1977. (Box 6)
    - Financial Statements, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - General correspondence and information, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - Roadless Area Review and Evaluation (RARE II) / Wilderness Areas, 1977-1978. (Box 7)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1978-1979. (Box 7)
    - General correspondence and information, 1978-1979. (Box 7)
    - Gypsy Moth Program, 1973-1979. (Box 7)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 7)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1978-1979. (Box 8)
    - Financial Statements, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - Forest Wardens Commissioned, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - General correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - Gypsy Moth Program, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - State Land Evaluation Advisory Committee, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
    - Southern Pin Bark Beetle Committee, 1975-1980. (Box 8)
  - Litter Control, Division of
    - Litter Prevention Program - General, 1974-1975. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - Requests, 1974-1975. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - Federal Campaign (Keep America Beautiful), 1974-1975. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - State Campaign (Keep Virginia Beautiful), 1974-1975. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - General, 1975-1976. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - State Campaign (Keep Virginia Beautiful), 1975-1976. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - Requests, 1975-1976. (Box 9)
    - Litter Prevention Program - General, 1976-1977. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - General, 1977-1978. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - General, 1978-1979. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - Quarterly Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - General, 1979-1980. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - Quarterly Reports, 1979-1980. (Box 9)
    - Litter Control - Grants, 1977-1980. (Box 9)
  - Mined Land Reclamation, Division of
    - General correspondence and information, 1967-1968. (Box 10)
    - General correspondence and information, 1969-1970. (Box 10)
    - General correspondence and information, 1970-1971. (Box 10)
    - Legislation, 1970-1971. (Box 10)
    - General correspondence and information, 1971-1972. (Box 10)
    - Legislation, 1971-1972. (Box 10)
    - Federal information and legisltion, 1972-1973. (Box 10)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC) - Green Springs Historic District (Louisa County), 1972-1973. (Box 10)
    - Property purchase (Big Stone Gap), 1970-1973. (Box 10)
    - Rules and Regulations Public Hearing - Board of Conservation and Economic Development - Coal Surface Mining, 1972. (Box 10)
    - Rules and Regulations, 1971-1973. (Box 10)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC) - Coal Mining Study - General, 1972-1973. (Box 11)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC) - Coal Mining Study - Meetings, 1972-1973. (Box 11)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC) - Coal Mining Study - Original Information to Members, 1972-1973. (Box 11)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures Completed, 1972-1974. (Box 11)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures Non-Compliance, 1972-1974. (Box 11)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): General, 1972-1974. (Box 11)
    - Mineral Other Than Coal (MOTC): Mining Tour, 1974 Apr. (Box 11)
    - Orphaned Land Advisory Committee, 1973-1974. (Box 11)
    - Coal Surface Mining Rules and Regulations - Public Hearing (Richmond), 1973 Dec. (Box 11)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC): Coal Mining Study Recommendations, 1973-1974. (Box 11)
    - Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC): Minerals Other Than Coal Study, 1973-1974. (Box 11)
    - Vulcan Materials, Green Springs, 1973-1974. (Box 11)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures Non-Compliance, 1974-1975. (Box 11)
    - Coal: General, 1974-1975. (Box 11)
    - Coal: Printing of Coal Rules and Regulations, 1974-1975. (Box 11)
    - Coal: Public Hearing on Rules and Regulations (coal amendments), 1974 Dec. (Box 11)
    - Federal Legislation: Mining Information, 1974-1975. (Box 11)
    - General: Correspondence and information, 1974-1975. (Box 12)
    - General: Hearings on Forfeitures, 1974-1975. (Box 12)
    - General: Newspaper clippings, 1974-1975. (Box 12)
    - General: Requests, 1974-1975. (Box 12)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures (#1), 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Boal: Bond Forfeitures (#2), 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Coal: General correspondence and information, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Coal: Legislation - Proposed increase in coal strip mining fees by 1976 General Assembly, 19. (Box 12)
    - Federal Legislation: Surface Mining Statistical Data, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - General: Correspondence and information, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - General: Miscellaneous, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - General: Newspaper clippings, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - General: Quarterly Reports, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - General: Requests for information, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): Bond Forfeitures, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): General correspondence and information, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): Laws in Other States, 1975-1976. (Box 12)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): Meeting, 1975 Dec. (Box 13)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): TVA Contract, 1976. (Box 13)
    - Mining Other Than Coal (MOTC): Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC) Study, 1975-1976. (Box 13)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures, 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    - Coal: Mining Methods and Drainage Control Handbook - Advisory Committee, 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    - Coal: Mining Methods and Drainage Control Handbook - Public Hearing, 1977 May. (Box 13)
    - Coal: General correspondence and information, 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    - Coal: Surface Mining Tour and Public Hearing (Southwest Virginia), 1976 Oct. (Box 13)
    - Coal: Surface Mining Tour, 1976 Sept. (Box 13)
    - Federal Legislation: Conformity of State Legislation to Federal Legislation, 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    - Federal Legislation: Surface Mining - House Resolution 2 and Senate Resolution 7, 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    - Federal Legislation: Surface Mining Statistical Data, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - Federal Legisltion: Testimony by Virginia on Resolution 2, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - General: Communications - Radio Equipment, 1975-1977. (Box 14)
    - General: Consultant Reports, 1975. (Box 14)
    - General: Miscellaneous, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - General: Quarterly Reports, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - General: Requests for Information, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - General: State Water Control Board (SWCB) / Mined Land Reclamation Memorandum of Understanding, 1974-1977. (Box 14)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) - Orphaned Land Reclamation, 1974-1977. (Box 14)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) - Land Tour, 1976 Dec. (Box 14)
    - Virginia Citizens for Better Reclamation, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal: Bond Forfeitures, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal: General correspondence and information, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal: Regulations, 1974-1977. (Box 14)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal: Virginia Legislative Advisory Committee Study, 1976-1977. (Box 14)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures - File No. 1, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures - File No. 2, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Coal: General correspondence and information, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Coal: State Water Control Board (SWCB) Memorandum of Understanding - Coal Program, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Federal Legislation: General correspondence and information, 1976-1978. (Box 15)
    - Federal Legislation: Lawsuit No. 77-2151 Virginia Dept. of Conservation and Economic Development v. U.S. Dept. of Interior - Federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act Conflict of Interest Provision, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Federal Legislation: Lawsuit No. 78-162 Lawsuit against Federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1877 - Surface Mining Regulation Litigation, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - Federal Legisltion: Public Hearing - Conformity to Federal Legislation (Richlands), 1978 Apr. (Box 15)
    - Federal Legislation: Surface Mining Amendments - Proposed, 19. (Box 15)
    - General: Correspondence and information, 1970-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Grundy Airport, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Inspectors/Foremen Training Certification Program, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Mines and Quarries - Oil and Gas Regulations, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Mines and Quarries - Proposed Merger, 1976-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Miscellaneous, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Orphaned Land, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Permit Operators, 1977-1978. (Box 15)
    - General: Personnel Field Handbook, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - General: Publications, 1973-1978. (Box 16)
    - General: Requests, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - General: Quarterly Reports, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - General: Statistical Data, 1971-1978. (Box 16)
    - General: Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) - Orphaned Land, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Asbestos, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Bond Forfeitures, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Bond Requirements, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): General correspondence and information, 1974-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Public Hearing - Rules and Regulations (Richmond), 1978 June. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Technical Advisory Committee, 1977-1978. (Box 16)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Virginia Advisory Legislative Committee (VALC) Study, 1970-1978. (Box 16)
    - Abandoned Mine Land: Orphaned Land - General correspondence and information, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Abandoned Mine Land: Orphaned Land Status Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Surface Mining Revenues, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Deep Mines, 1974-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: General correspondence and information, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Miscellaneous, 1973-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Governor's Mined Land Reclamation Advisory Committee, 1977-1979. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Public Hearing - New and Revised Coal Mining Regulations (Abingdon), 1978 July. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Public Hearing - Permanent Regulation Program (Big Stone Gap), 1979 June. (Box 17)
    - Coal: Public Hearing - Alternatives to Federal Rules and Regulations (Richlands), 1978 Nov. (Box 17)
    - Coal: State Water Control Board (SWCB) Memorandum of Understanding - Coal Program, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Federal Legislation: Abandoned Mine Lands, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
    - Federal Legislation: Comments on federal legislation, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: Environmental Impact Statements - Federal Coal Management Progrm, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: House Oversight Hearing, 1979 Mar. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: House Oversight Hearing, 1979 June. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: General correspondence and information, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: Lawsuit PL 95-87; 78-0224-B Virginia Surface Mining and Reclamation Association (VSMRA) and Town of Wise v. Andrus; and 79-1146 VSMRA v. Andrus (Court of Appeals), 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: Dept. of Interior - Office of Surface Mining News Releases, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: Public Hearing - Proposed Rules for Permanent Regulation (Washington, DC), 1978 Oct. (Box 18)
    - Federal Legislation: St. Charles Reclamation Project, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Communications - Telephone equipment, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Film Activities, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Miscellaneous, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Inspector/Foreman Training Certification Program, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Mines and Quarries, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: News Articles, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Quarterly Reports, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Technical Services, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Virginia Citizens for Better Reclamation, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - General: Virginia Surface Mining and Reclamation Association, 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Bond Forefeiture, 1978-1979. (Box 19)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): General correspondence and information, 1978-1979. (Box 19)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Minerals Reclamation Fund, 1978-1979. (Box 19)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Rules and Regulations - Development and Printing, 1978 June. (Box 19)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Virginia Vermiculite mining in Louisa County, 1973-1979. (Box 19)
    - Abandoned Mine Lands: Federal Legislation, 1979-1980. (Box 19)
    - Abandoned Mine Lands: Orphaned Land - Correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 19)
    - Abandoned Mine Lands: Orphaned Land Status Reports, 1979-1980. (Box 19)
    - Abandoned Mine Lands: St. Charles and Oakwood Gob Pile Projects, 1979-1980. (Box 19)
    - Coal: Bond Forfeitures, 1979-1980. (Box 19)
    - Coal: Complaints, 1971-1980. (Box 19)
    - Coal: General correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Coal: Governor's Mined Land Reclamation Advisory Committee, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Coal: Printing - Coal Regulations, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Coal: State Water Control Board (SWCB) Memorandum of Understanding - Coal Program, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: Comments on federal legislation, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: Committee on Surface Mining and Reclamation (COSMAR) - Federal MOTC Study, 1978-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: General correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: Lawsuit No. 78-2190 - Surface Mining Interim Regulation Litigation (DC Circuit Court), 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: Office of Surface Mining - Reclamation and Enforcement, 1977-1980. (Box 20)
    - Federal Legislation: Public Hearing - State Regulations Controlling Surface Mining, 1980 Jan. (Box 20)
    - General: Consultants, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Film Activities, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Misecllaneous, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Quarterly Reports, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Revenues, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Virginia Aggregate Association, 1979-1980. (Box 20)
    - General: Virginia Citizens for Better Reclamation, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - General: Virginia Surface Mining and Reclamation Association, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Abandoned Mine Land Advisory Committee for MOTC Program, 1978-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Bond Forfeitures, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Complaints, 1972-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): Drainage Handbook, 1977-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): General correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC): W. R. Grace - Greensprings, 1972-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: Blasting Activities, 1977-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: Coal Forms, 1967-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: Minerals Other Than Coal (MOTC) Forms, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: General correspondence and information, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: Permit applications, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
    - Technical Services: Training and Certification Program, 1979-1980. (Box 21)
  - Mineral Resources, Division of
    - Magnetometer Survey, 1962-1963. (Box 22)
    - General correspondence and information, 1970-1973. (Box 22)
    - General correspondence and information, 1974-1975. (Box 22)